# **CURRICULUM VITAE**

## Kritika Mazumder

GIS Analyst

Email: mazumder.kritika@gmail.com

Phone No. +91 8860336791 Current Location: Noida, NCR

I intend to work with absolute zeal for all the challenges associated to my domain with full dedication wherein I can utilize my expertise, acquire new skills and work towards achieving collective goals for the organization.

#### **AREAS OF EXPERTISE**

GIS & Remote Sensing Technologies, GIS Data Analytics, Image processing, Photogrammetry, UAS Technologies, Project Management and Business Analytics

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2 Years 6 months

SenseBird Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

July 2017 - Present

#### **GIS Analyst**

## **Roles and Responsibilities:**

- Responsible for UAV data processing acquired for various projects and businesses using suits
  of image processing softwares
- Advance data analytics using Artificial Intelligence (AI) powered platforms
- Framing comprehensive reports along with data interpretations and necessary deliverable outputs
- Drafting proposals/presentations and designing products and services for clients
- Scheduling timelines for project deliverables and look after project implementations

## **UAV Projects:**

Agriculture

Roads & Highways

Mining

 Developmental Authorities for Smart City Planning Industrial Inspection

Software Interfaces: Pix4D, Global Mapper, ArcGIS, Precession Mapper, Airware, ContextCapture

Weather-risk Management Services

July 2016 - June 2017

#### **GIS Expert**

## **Roles and Responsibilities:**

- Crop Health Monitoring (NDVI), Yield and Acreage Estimation (Kharif & Rabi Crops)
- Flood-Mapping for vulnerable and affected areas
- Diseases identification in agricultural crops
- Change detection in crop health and developing Elevation model for drainage mapping
- LULC mapping for crop monitoring using supervised and unsupervised classification

#### **Projects:**

Verifying Agricultural Insurance claims for various clients and providing consultation for crop health and damage.

#### **SOFTWARE COMPETENCIES**

Arc Map/View/Catalogue (10.2), ERDAS Imagine, QGIS, Global Mapper, Geomatica, Pix4D, PrecissionMapper, AIRWARE, GoogleEarth

#### **INTERNSHIPS**

Defense Terrain & Research Laboratory, DRDO, Ministry Of Defense, New Delhi.

Worked on individual project on the topic "Geospatial Analysis of Thematic Layers and use of GIS Applications for Terrain Mapping: A case study of a hilly area in a local district of West Bengal"

#### Responsibilities:

- Proficient in extraction of Thematic Layers, with different levels of classification with respective color codes of satellite imageries
- Performing Site Suitability Analysis for Multi-criteria Decision Evaluation
- Performing Watershed Analysis & Delineation of Watershed boundary and Morphometric Analysis using Arc GIS (10.2) and ERDAS IMAGINE 14
- Assam Remote Sensing & Application Center (ARSAC), Assam Science Technology & Environmental Council (ASTEC)

Worked on a project entitled "Study of Crop Dynamics using Remote Sensing and GIS Techniques: A case study of flood affected Mayang Revenue Circle of Morigaon District, Assam"

#### Responsibilities:

- Handling image processing software (ERDAS version 14 and Geomatica) and GIS software (Arc GIS version 10)
- Worked on Geo-referencing, digitization, image enhancement techniques, accuracy assessment and field verification in the process of the project.

#### **ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS**

Course	University/Board	Year
M.Sc. (GIS & Remote Sensing)	AMITY UNIVERSITY, NOIDA	2014-2016
B.A (Hons.) Geography	UNIVERSITY OF DELHI	2010-2013
Intermediate	CBSE	2008-2010
Matriculation	CBSE	2008

\_\_\_\_